Only the hard and strong may call themselves Spartans.
Only the hard.
Only the strong.
We march. For our lands, for our families,
for our freedoms. We march.
Leonidas! What a pleasant surprise.
This morning's full of surprises.
We've been tricked. Can't be more than a few hundred.
This is a surprise.
Silence!
We heard Sparta was on the warpath, and we were eager to join forces.
If it is blood you seek, you're welcome to join us.
But you bring only this handful of soldiers against Xerxes?
I see I was wrong to expect Sparta's commitment to at least match our own.
Doesn't it?
You there! What is your profession?
I'm a potter... sir.
And you, Arcadian! What is your profession?
Sculptor, sir.
Sculptor.
And you?
Blacksmith.
Spartans! What is your profession?!
HA-OOH! HA-OOH! HA-OOH!
You see, old friend? I brought more soldiers than you did.